Ok so, hello everyone listening, this is
obviously Everscale incubator. I belive we're
on show number one.
I'm speaking today with Norton who is bringing
his project to us, Fidosafe
So hi Norton. Good to have you here! Would
you introduce yourself?
Yes, sure, Ben, thanks for providing the
stage
for presenting my project, actually cannot
say much about myself, like I'm ordinary
guy
developer, crypto enthusiast, and, yes, I'm
like
keeping an eye on the Everscale blockchain
for a while, but did not have a chance to
find applicable cases that I can implement
but, yes, recently I've found a niche
that sounds interesting to me, and today
I would like to
say a few words about this niche, describe
the target
audience, its pains, its needs, and share
some insights, and, actually, like it
was the grounds for, this project,
Fidosafe, that I'll also maybe share
during this broadcast. Ok, well, in this
case
I think we should probably dive straight
into it and
... doing a screensharing
aha, yes.
so can everyone see that pitch there on the
screen if I've shared the right screen?
Yes, I guess the wrong screen, it is a website
page
Wrong screen? Yeaw. Here we go. Yes. Go to...
We've got the infinite loop, I apologise
guys.
let's close that down. More used to working
with
Zoom, yeah. Yes, me too, that's why I didn't
want to share.
there we go. so. can everyone see the pich?
We should see Fidosafe
on the screen. Yeah, I do.
Ok, excellent. Let's just quickly roll through
this
We won't going through every point on the
document, as I've got a few questions, I'll
try to keep it
a little more informal, but yeah, obviously,
if you could give us just
a very quick high-level interview of what
is Fidosafe.
Hm, ok, just to warm up
I would like to say a few words about the
name, so the name originates from
actually Latin, and Fido means the first
person
verb, like "I trust",
like the safe that I trust, Fidosafe, but
recently
somebody shared a reference that there is
a famous player
chess player, Vladimir Fidoseev, and yes,
from that time, when I hear Fidosafe, I think
about chess.
This is a very hot topic with the World Championship
of course. Yeah, uh. But basically in a nutshell
this is a service, webservice where
actually people can jointly
manage their financial resources, so that
we would have
multiple custodians using different wallets
who can sign transactions
and perform some operations as community
as DAO, yeah.
Touching into your first point, who is this
product aimed at?
who is going to use Fidosafe?
Yeah,it might
sound surprising
that there are some B2B tools around on the
market
so not only personal accounts in crypto nowadays
but also business
accounts start start penetrating the crypto
surface
more and more, and of course market starts
preparing
some tools for catering to these accounts.
THat's why I can describe
these companies as small
crypto investment firms, or maybe crypto
brockers, and possibly communities who also
come together
to make financial decisions together, other
audiences for the shared using are of
the accounts are for example are miners or
exchanges, but they are I guess too big to
fit the Fidosafe requirements
so that I would just
limit the users to
small and medium crypto businesses theat
we will call crypto funds
or crypto firms. Ok, so essentially blockchain
centric small and medium enterprises and
businesses which have to
follow more formal path. Yeah. And so, again,
this is a very nicely laid out slide presentation,
what is it that there is a need
that will why they are ready products that
use these people
There are the tools, and the tools serve
actually the existing blockchains
if one of these companies
would like to start their operations on Everscale,
then they would need to
to uh
adjust to also continue
operations from here, and they could have
different options
for this
that's ok, I've thought someone bombing,
now all good
as you say, this is the solution which
already exist on the chains in the forms,
but there is
obiously... I'll let you explain aside this
slide yourself if you want, existing solutions
so yes,
to prepare to this presentation I checked
the market
and tried to find the tools that people use
and tried to investigate which functionality
is built into these
tools, so that here is my list that originated
from
maybe two hours of searching
of course there are more solutions on the
market, but these are the
prominent ones, and basing on the
solutions I can make some assumptions on
what these businesses should require
and the functionality of these solutions
is actually
is pretty much the same, so that if we go
to maybe the second slide
that could help us, we will find out that
in the bare minimum it will require three
things actually. First: some tools for collective
decision making, so that multiple custodians
can
vote for this or that or against this or
that decision
then user management, the ability to assign
roles
and to add more people, remove people from
the list of custodians,
I mean onboarding and offboarding employees
actually
Sorry, I believe I've got the right temp
here, we can kind say an exmple, so that
this is actually
the product doing it here, I belive you've
added
a custodian here as an example transaction
you showed me earlier
Yes, we can see that happening, sorry, carry
on...
... and the third maybe the most tricky
one is auditing facilities
the ability to see the historical
log and be able to understand who did what
and when
and when I started with Everscale,
I tried a few multisig accounts
and actually, and none of them had
open source code, but there were compiled
versions
of these multisig accounts, and using these
accounts is
it was really tricky to understand the history
of operations
maybe it was something wrong with me, but
I feel total obscurity, that was one of the
reasons to actually
create something where the transactions are
obvious
you can at every moment glance at a transaction
and see
its details and who confirmed or rejected
it
and what was inside this transaction, what
operation should happen
so essentially just comming to this part
of the slide
there are solutions
which kinda do the task that Fidosafe does,
but you do it in more refined
manner which is more suitable for the target
audience you're aiming for here
Right, actually it is a service, and not
a wallet,
so that users are not obliged to
to come to this new wallet and operate only
in this
wallet, comparing to, for example, Oberton
when you need to forcefully switch to this
solution
for all your operations, but instead it is
a webservice that uses different wallets
for a very-very concrete purpose
for signing multisig transactions and for
managing multisig transactions, and for
managing the related operations, so, yes,
on the one hand there are
wallets that can potentially implement the
same
but it is not their specialization, they
are busy with
other things like implementing DeBots, implementing
trueNFTs
implementing other features, that their customers
actually require
instead, why would they
turn to some other niche market and start
doing something
different, it does not make sense. Yes of
course, I understand that
completely, that makes a lot of sense, so
obviously these
other solution providers it's an option,
it's a feature
of these products, but it's not their product
as you say.
Yeah, that's brilliant. Comming to the next
slide, you've turned this one Pains, obviously,
so we're just going to touch on these, but
what on the Pains like you say your target
audience at the moment.
Yes, also started to
discuss the pains, but the main pain so actually
how to
proceed with operations when you go to Everscale
for example, you had Gnosis to govern your
operations
in Etherium, and you just look for the similar
stuff
and you have these four options
Firstly, you can revive an existing multisig
wallet
and try to somehow operate under it with
ll its obscurity and limitations, maybe it
is possible, it is
like dooing accounting in Google Spreadsheets,
so it is possible, but it
is not that convenient. Then they could
implement their in-house solution
and in this case it would be also ok, but
they would need to spend money
and would need to spend time to implement
this
and the biggest issue is that their code
will not be open source
it will be an in-house solution
that means it won't be audited, this means
it could be possibly prone to
errors or maybe some hacker attacks
so they will always run risk of losing their
money
I guess it's not that convenient
to always live in this risk
Right, risk is not convenient in that sense
and the third option is that they can calml
wait for somebody
some authority like Metamask Institutional
when the biggest vendor implements this
function for Everscale
but I guess that unfortunately they would
have to wait for a bit while.
and because
something very extraordinary should happen
for these conservative providers to actually
onboard
Everscale, the blockchain that is on the
three hundred and eighty fourth place?
why would they? maybe they would, but
it will require some time, and I have doubts
that
even if they start doing this, they will
also look on the market
for the comparable solutions
and they would just buy this solution and
adjust it
Of course the technical aspect of Everscale
with we're right now would that
they all gonna require time for beginning
integration, so I completely understand what
you mean
the 4th is
to find an alternative and
a month ago I stumbled upon
the alternatives, and maybe
that's why I started to working on this project
if you know any good alternatives around,
please let me know
It sounds like you're definitely developing
something which
there is a need for at Everscale firm as
far as I can see
so this next slide kinda moves us into more
of the overall market
side of things, I donno if you want to quickly
walk us through this one?
Yes, so the idea for the this slide was
actually if we have this bere minimum
in the existing solutions, what if we
just implement this bare minimum and sit
and wait for companies
to start going into Everscale for their operational
activity?
Sounds like a good plan. But actually not
because these B2B vendors
do not sit on their ass and they also evolve
and the whole defi
land and landscape evolves
so that they develop new and new of working
with financial tools
firstly it was liquidity providing,
then it was marginal farming,
then it was this NFT and cross-chain farming
there were bridges, then there were diferent
kinds of protocols
different kinds of networks, and people get
confused
and they would like some professionals to
manage their money
because they do not want
to continuesly be fed by more and more information
and because they get lost, so they want to
have professional brockers
it is the reflection of the mutual funds
in our real life, so people, the lend their
money
for the interest
and of course brockers get their percent
from
this money for their operations, so from
what I see
from the communication with the Gnosis team,
I recently had the communication,
the are starting to build the new team which
actually focuses on just precisely that
so they have this Gnosis safe which is a
B2B tool
and they want to make it work for
the normal users, for the private accounts
and another thing is SuperDAO
they raised one million dollars, seed round
with lots of funds
but still it means that this topic
of actually making joint decisions and creating
DAO
using smart contracts is vibrant currently
among people so that they easily can
get investments on the one hand and succeed
in implementing the solution that users require
on the other
Yeah, of course, well, you've done your homework,
always good to say
so we're gonna talk a bit about
the future of Fidosafe very quickly
so I see
two steps as I mentioned on my forum thread,
the first is to actually implement this bare
minimum
with transactions, users and settings, so
that every bussiness which wants to start
their operations on Everscale can start doing
this
with Fidosafe, and step 2 would be to evolve,
to make it DAO
where people can profit from these B2B tools
I see it as
system where everything is transparent
you can see how much money you want to lend
you will see how much money you will get
after some period, of course your money will
be blocked
for some time, I guess it would be something
like in real life, when we have only quartely
payments
one per quarter and also
this smart contract can
give the transparency
in terms of how much money these brockers
have earned
and if it is reasonable to stick to them
or maybe switching to somebody else, like
finding another
company or a firm with better stats.
Excellent, thanks, very comprehensive slides
Thank you very much for putting it together
and sharing it with us
Let's take it a little more informally
I just wannt know a little more about your
background
so you say you're a developer? Not really
So I must have misinterpreted that.
I would say that I'm an enterpreneur,
and what I like to do it actually create
new value, so I had a history of
a few startups, and some of them were
this or that successful
at least I had tracktion on some of them
but maybe did some mistakes so that cannot
bragging about something very familiar that
you are all aware of
The only really failure in life is not trying
again so... Yes. So waht were these startups?
Can you give us an idea about these things?
Ah...
I would like not to reveal it, sorry. Oh,
no, you don't have to tell what the exact
product,
but what areas you were working in? What
type of startups? It?
Ok,
Funny enough, they were all B2B services,
so that it is my
primary target, I understand
that it is harder to get B2B accounts
but as soon as you acquire them, it is easier
in
terms of financials, in terms of statistics,
in terms of
everything, in terms of churn especially.
yeah!
I've worked in a several sales positions
in my past, and obviously B2B
is a much longer pipeline with onboarding,
but
when customers are onboarded, there is much
more professional relationship
so yeah, that's brilliant. Just to kinda
verify that.. was it mostly kind of software
as a service, sort of things or?
Yeah,
So you're mostly in a B2B SaaS.
B2B2C SaaS
and so with this project
have you got a team with you, or you're working
on your own? You're outsourcing?
How is it working there?
Yeah, currently I work on my own.
but I cannot call myself a developer because
actually I
don't have technical education in Computer
Science
of course I have a great deal of experience
in coding, but
do not have an experience of corporate coding
so that coding in team and this stuff and
one of the reasons also to start this product
was to
get acquainted with the blockchain and the
technology
and understand how the smart contracts work
on Everscale and
it was a kinda learning curve
for me, and the learning curve, so yes, the
learning curve for everyone around here I
think, I'm still learning every day
Sorry,
Yeah, I can code, and you can see from
the repository that yeah, every line of code
was written by me
if you want to spot any refinements
please let me know
Excellent, so all your code is in open source,
so everyone can have a look at it. Yeah.
That's great to know.
One quick follow-up question from that:
you say "learning", how long have you been
in the space?
in crypto currency? just out of interest.
in crypto, not that long,
I guess from
You know, the last spike
Maybe from the beginning of this year.
Somewhere there in January I hopped into
this market
because everything grew.
I wish I'de went in the market in January
I told you. That is fantastic.
So regarding Fidosafe, about cold-heart details
about the product, what have you achieved
so far, is it a fully-functioning?
Is it ready to go? Where you are at in kinda
MVP roadmap sort of things?
this bare minimum functionality
has this management
transaction management, user management,
session management
and also sending value
and the question of sending value is not
ready yet
so with onboarding of this feature
I would say that I would have this bare minimum
MVP
or course some bells and whistles need to
be added
for example validation checks, notifications
about removal and so on
of course users like and developers do not
like to implement
but I think in the nutshell
everything is ready besides the transfer
transaction itself
Excellent. Apart from items you've just mentioned,
like you say with the transfer transaction
and all these bells and whistles
what are your immediate plans
in terms of one-two-three months
I would say
... onboarding that kind of thing.
I would say that it would not get into
havily into the development
but rather
I would start trying to communicate with
these companies how actually use
this software in different other blockchains
and will try to attract them to Everscale
but for this I would need
this software to adhere to basic requirements
that they will need, and firstly is the security
what I would need
once all the code is ready
it to accomplish a number of code audits
and also publish them and be able to
run some campaign among the community to
encourage reporting bugs
if people see them
Excellent. Just to kinda re-iterate for a
people who are really slow on technical side
like me, obviously Everscale incubator
it has immediate plans looking for projects
to list on DappRadar specifically
would you say
that Fidosafe is 90% ready?
once it has the audits and the transfer function
added?
Yes, but you must understand that it takes
time
Soon is everyone's favorite word
In Everscale and blockchain projects
but if you put a timeline to this again assuming
the best case with this?
Ok, let's divide the things into technical
-
implementation, development and verification
and in terms of technical completion I guess
we're no longer than a month away from the
publication
in terms of the technicals
we'd be looking, yeah, I'm mustoring to myself,
but don't worry, carry on
and in terms of adoption and reviews
and some kind of input from the users, I
would say it will also require some time
and of course it depends on the community
so that I would rely on the feedback from
the community
Yeah, of course feedback loop, that's brilliant.
And so,
We're getting through my questions very and
very efficiently, but you're very good at
this
What would you say gonna be the biggest hurdles,
so what's gonna
be the biggest potential road blocks, stops
in your path?
I guess the biggest limiting factor is time
of course
because I have 9-to-5 job
and it could have some deadlines, I have
family
to manage, and this also means that I'm kind
of
vulnerable because I can turn to something
else
and won't be able to devote much time
to this product by refocusing on
my work, home, my family, etc., so
that I guess this would be the biggest risk
as in solo-founder startups
in general, and the best way to handle it
is
to maybe share
the vision of the next steps and build up
a team who can also help
Ok, that leads quite nicely, so what exactly
are you
looking to get from the Everscale incubator
what help and support do you really need
to take this forward
Initially
I would love to have
this problem with the security solved, so
that
if it requires some effort from the community
members
it would be great as it requires some
costs to perform these audits
also ok, but I would like the community to
help me with collecting the
necessary money to accomplish this
so first and foremost in your immediate kinda
plan you need some kind of helpie
in terms of auditing costs involved
to be where it needs to be in terms of security.
Yes.
the second would be to actually
guarantee to the first users, first commercial
users
that this software works as intended, so
that I would also like
to have the beta testers program
where people can try it and report whatever
they find
for this I would need some PR
to make my product noticed among the people
who actually
may need it and be able to
ping me around and join my
Telegram channel or something like that so
that they can also contribute
with their ideas, with their features
in terms of the Everscale community
you're speaking with the right man, sure
I can help you out as much as possible with
that if we go forward
Excellent, so we've got auditing costs, beta
testing programs,
these are both the areas where you need support,
is there anything else?
Again, immediate.
For immediate I guess yes, for the long-term
goals I also
would like to have
this PR support, maybe copywriters help with
articles and publications to forums and catalogs
and maybe
some help with communicating with some external
entities
whe trying to helping get started
with this new blockchain
and ultimately when we have a plan for
the next steps, it would be great to also
have a help about team building
but of course it is currently
only on the horizon
not the shirt-term goal. Yes, of course,
it sounds like you've got quite a solid plan
in place
let's go to the speculative side of things
assuming that everything goes through and
well with the Everscale incubator
and you receive all the help you need in
the shirt term
let's put a rough date on it, where would
you see
the product in terms of usage
consumer customer figures that kind of things
one year from now and three years from now,
what would be your very optimistic outlook
for this?
not very optimistic but yours
I don't wanna you to sound too sunshining
you know, your realistically
best-case scenario
Ok, I guess that even if we
lure even one company
you must understand that their operational
volumes
are starting from one million dollars, so
that
it would be success to me at least
to have even one corporate client that uses
this software on the day-to-day basis
if their volume is like
this 1 mln dollars
than the transactional costs would be
in a year
calculation it would be a few
tens of thousands dollars
even this would cover some
budget for bread and butter
yeah
ok, one kind of
stickler problem I could see possibly, so
you'd need
help with auditing and beta testing and such,
would there be any
insurance liability, accountability issues
here because obviously as
I understand it's the big part of the institutional
need is
that for this accountability, they don't
wanna be responsible for
their own keys and own coins. of course,
I guess nobody in crypto is responsible for
anything
and every time you use a product, it has
a big
disclaimer that "We are not responsible for
anything"
and please do your own research, so I guess
for these
these tools it is also be the truth
because in the majority of cases
in the similar products the completed code
audits
are basically enough to say that the solution
is secure
and then users are invited to have their
own research
but all the risks are actually on them
ok, and obviously the crypto currency is
ever-changing regulatory landscape
do you see any issues with it at all coming
up?
have you already done your homework in
terms of legal due dilligent side?
No, I didn't, and what I see here
it is of course a regulated activity
and the entities which do these kind of
brockership operations, they require some
kind of certificates
they are unders some regulations, definitely
but these regulations normally lie
outside of the software they use, for example
they need to have a brockership license,
they need some docs
to keep crypto, to sell and buy crypto, but
this doesn't
have any connection to the software they
use for performing
their operations at least on the surface,
hopefully
Yes, of course a little more deepdigging
required just in case
but given your knowledge of the landscape
this is
forced down to individual liabilities actually
Brilliant, so what we're gonna do, Norton,
is we just gonna take
a very quick two-minute break
I'm gonna refill my coffee, and we're gonna
see if anyone in the group has any questions
for you
let me just find, too many Telegram groups
out there
Incubator, so...
any questions?
right, so don't know if you wanna grab yourself
a very quick drink, I just gonna go get my
coffee up, and we
come back and see if anyone in the group
has any questions and see if any more pop
up into my little head
In two minutes, right? Yes, just a couple
of minutes. Brilliant, speak to you in a
moment.
I've got my coffee filled up, guys, I think...
As far as I can see no questions in the group
as of yet, so
I believe it was a pretty comprehensive run
through today, yeah, anything you'd like
to add?
Oh, I'm really excited about your questions
and I think we've covered everything that
I wanted
Thank you very much for this deep and detailed
interview, you were great, Ben, thanks.
Thank you.
I'm sure you know I used to do slightly frivolous
style of hosting
it's been nice having you in a more serious
conversation
which is good to expand, it's been a brilliant
meeting, Norton,
and I'm very excited to find out how your
progect progresses
you have a great rest of your day, thank
you for listending a lot
have a great day